Guide to the William Goldman papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series IV: Manuscripts
  - Subseries 4.4: Short Stories
    - The Hanging of Mrs. St. Claire; t.ms.; The Ice Cream Eat; t.ms. (3 drafts); Blam; t.ms.; Thunk (2 drafts) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Dirt; t.ms. (3 drafts); J8; t.ms. with autograph notes (3 drafts) If You Listen You Can Almost Hear It; (2 drafts) (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Note for The Wife; Abstract of The Temple of Gold; t.ms.; The Ice Cream Eat; t.ms.; A Ride on a Choo-Choo; t.ms.; untitled; t.ms.; The Simple Pleasures of the Rich; t.ms.; The Simple Pleasures of the Rich; a.ms.; The Aztec City; t.ms.; A Suite at the Plaze; t.ms.; The Last One Home t.ms. fragment; The Second Day of School; t.ms. with autograph notes; Autograph notes; The Craziest Day; t.ms.; The Man Who Beat Packy MacFarland; t.ms.; Fire on Kessler Street; t.ms.; Till the Right Girl Comes Along;; The Army; t.ms.; autograph and typescript notes, legal pad of notes; On the Diamond; t.ms.; untiltled fragments; t.ms. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - The Simple Pleasues of the Rich; Quiet; untitled; Tale for a Rainy Afternoon; Dirt; The Most Beautiful Girl in New York; Feeny a.ms.; Tale for a Rainy Afternoon; untitled treatment for a play; Beat Up in the Bronx; unidentified fragment, p.91; autograph notes for ?; draft and materials for Huntington Forsyth; Till the Right Girl Comes Along; Beat in the Bronx; Da Vinci revised; Til the Right Girls Come Along notes; Fire on Kessler Street; untitled with notes; Fire on Kessler Street; Da Vinci (Box 4, Folder 1 - 4)
    - Three Cheers for the Prince of Morocco; God Rest ye Merry, Cromatons; Prayer; Untitled; Fragment of God Rest ye Merry, Cromatons; Prayer and A Few Days In Between (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Now I am Six (2 drafts); Something Blue (3 drafts); Notes for stories and plays; Nagurski, [ca. 1962] (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Shaw, Irwin Five Decades [short stories] (Box 102, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 4.5: Teleplays
    - Something in Fur by David Shaber and WIlliam Goldman; Cash and Carry by Bruce Geller and William Goldman; Hog in a Hot Sump Pump; Untitled film dialogue pages; The Green Cunt by William Goldman and David Shaber (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Madonna and Child by James and William Goldman (2 darfts); Blood, Sweat and Stanley Poole by James and William Goldman (Box 5, Folder 4 - 6)
    - Mr. Horn [Teleplay] (Box 72, Folder 1 - 6)
  - Subseries 4.6: Musicals
    - A Family Affair [Notes and drafts] (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - A Family Affair [Scripts] (Box 6, Folder 1 & 2)
      [Book by James and William Goldman, lyrics by James Goldman an John Kander, music by John Kander]
    - A Family Affair [Final production version] (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - A Family Affair [Script revisions], December 1959 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - No Way to Treat a Lady by Seymour Krenzer and Miles McGee (2 drafts); Something Blue (3 drafts); Notes for stories and plays; Nagurski; Notes, reports and drafting materials pertaining to No Way to Treat a Lady (Box 6, Folder 6 - 8)
    - Memorabilia from the musical of No Way to Treat a Lady, [ca. 1963] (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Notes and ephemera pertaining to Family Affair, [ca. 1963] (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - The Man Who Owned Chicago (2 drafts) (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - The Man Who Owned Chicago (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - The Man Who Owned Chicago, [ca. 1963], (2 drafts, 1 spiral notebook of notes, ) (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Boys and Girls Together, ( Typescript and autograph draft and notes, ) (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Boys and Girls Together, ( Typescript and autograph draft and notes, ) (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Boys and Girls Together, [ca. 1963], ( Typescript and autograph draft and notes, ) (Box 7, Folder 7)
      [aka Magic Town]
    - Boys and Girls Together, [n.d.], (5 drafts in five folders, ) (Box 8, Folder 1 - 5)
      [All are incomplete and all have autograph notes and corrections]
    - Boys and Girls Together fragment; Boys and Girls Together ephemera (Box 9, Folder 1 & 2)
    - Materials relating to the musical Company (Box 136, Folder 3)
    - Michael Stewart and Fran and John Pascal George M! Music and Lyrics by George M. Cohan (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Ernest Kinoy Golden Rainbow Music and lyrics by Walter Marks (Box 19, Folder 4 & 5)
    - N. Richard Nash The Happy Time Lyrics by Fred Ebb, Music by John kander (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Marc Richards Hellzapoppin '67 Music and lyrics by Marian Grudeff and Raymond Jessel (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Henry Sweet Henry by Nunnally Johnson, music and lyrics by Bob Merrill (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Materials relating to the musical Company (Box 136, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 4.7: Non Fiction
    - ADVENTURES IN THE SCREEN TRADE
      - Adventures in the Screen Trade [nonfiction 1983], 1981-1982, ( Notes, research, draft pages, ) (Box 132, Folder 1 - 6)
      - Drafts (Box 134, Folder 3 - 6)
      - Photocopies and one magazine pertaining to Adventures in the Screen Trade non fiction.; Photocpopies of Motion Picture Herald articles pertaining to the ranking of motion picture stars in the sixties and seventies.; Rolling Stone 18 March 1982 (Box 528, Folder 7)
      - Photocopies of research materials Adventures in the Screen Trade non fiction.; Photocpopies of Motion Picture Herald articles pertaining to Burt Reynolds career (Box 528, Folder 8)
    - THE SEASON
      - Manuscript notes (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - Typescript drafts (Box 30, Folder 2 - 7)
      - Drafts or parts of drafts in various states of editing (Box 31, Folder 1 - 5)
      - Printer's proof (Box 31, Folder 6)
      - Various proofs (Box 32, Folder 1 - 4)
      - Clippings and reviews (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - WAIT TILL NEXT YEAR
      - Unpublished nonfiction co-written with Mike Lupica aka "Broken Plays", 1988, ( Various drafts and proofs of unpublished work, ) (Box 156, Folder 1-6)
  - Subseries 4.8: Journalism
    - Notes on Ross MacDonlad article and interview (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Notes and material relating to William Goldman's review of Irwin Shaw for the New York Times (Box 102, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 4.9: Ghostwriting
    - PAPILLON
      - Papillon materials; Dry Guillotine by Rene Belbenoit; Papillion by Henri Charriere (2 copies); Notes and early drafts of the screeplay Papillion by William Goldman (uncredited) (Box 44, Folder 5-7)
      - Second and third drafts of the screenplay based on the novel by Henri Charriere (Box 45, Folder 1-6)
    - MEMOIRS OF AN INVISIBLE MAN
      - Novel Memoirs of an Invisible Man by H.F. Saint (Box 157, Folder 2)
      - Notes, research and draft pages for Memoirs of an Invisible Man (Box 157, Folder 3 & 4)
      - First draft of screenplay Memoirs of an Invisible Man (Box 157, Folder 5)
      - Memoirs of an Invisible Man, 1988, ( First and second drafts of the screenplay, ) (Box 158, Folder 1-6)
      - Memoirs of an Invisible Man, 1987, ( Screenplay (drafts including late drafts written by Robert Collector and Dana Olsen), ) (Box 159, Folder 1-6)
    - TWINS
      - Early drafts (Box 172, Folder 3-6)
      - Various versions of the fourth draft of the screenplay, 1988 (Box 173, Folder 1-6)
        [The following writers all had a hand in this project: William Osborne, William Davies, Timothy Harris, Herschel Weingrod, and William Goldman]
    - INDECENT PROPOSAL
      - Multiple drafts of the script by Amy Holden Jones with revisions by William Goldman, 1991 (Box 194, Folder 1-6)
      - Various drafts doctored by William Goldman, 1992 (Box 195, Folder 1-7)
      - Various drafts (Box 196, Folder 1-4)
    - LAST ACTION HERO
      - First pass at doctoring (Box 199, Folder 6)
      - Four drafts of The Last Action Hero doctored by William Goldman, written by Adam Lett, Shane Black and David Arnott (Box 200, Folder 1-4)
    - DOLORES CLAIBORNE
      - Dolores Claiborne by Tony Gilroy (Box 201, Folder 1 & 2)
      - Screenplay and research materials (Box 210, Folder 1-6)
    - MISSION IMPOSSIBLE 2
      - Drafts (Box 211, Folder 1 & 2)
  - Subseries 4.10: Lectures
    - ADVENTURES IN THE SCREEN TRADE
      - NYU and Columbia university lectures at the time of Adventures in the Screen Trade (Box 131, Folder 7 & 8)
      - Columbia University lecture, December 1981 (Box 131, Folder 8)
      - Oberlin Commencement Address and Wait until Next Year unpublished nonfiction; research, 1985 (Box 152, Folder 1 - 7)
      - Women in Hollywood lecture (Box 189, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 4.11: Interviews
    - Notes on Ross MacDonlad article and interview (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Interview with the film makers of A Bridge Too Far (Box 88, Folder 4 & 5)
    - Interviews for Rescue (Box 123, Folder 2 - 8)
    - Rescue! screenplay, 1980-1981; Research, clippings and interviews for the novel Rescue! (Box 124, Folder 1-6)
    - Interview with John Brady (Box 127, Folder 3)
    - Interview with George Roy Hill re. Adventures in the Screen Trade (Box 133, Folder 3)
    - Interview with Gordon Willis (Box 133, Folder 4)
    - Interview with John Brady (Box 133, Folder 5)
    - Interview with Robert Evans (Box 133, Folder 6)
    - Interview with Gareth Wigan (Box 134, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 4.12: Biography
    - Sir Richard Burton, a Biography, !987 (Box 161, Folder 1)
    - Sir Richard Burton notes (Box 161, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 4.13: Thesis
    - The Shape of the World. t.ms.; The Good Things of the Earth;. a.ms.; Assorted writing exercises. a.ms.; The Two bears. t.ms.; Untitled fragment. t.ms.; Whom the Gods would Destroy.... t.ms.; M is for the Million Things. t.ms.; What Lamp Has Destiny to Guide Her Little Children Stumbling in the Dark. t.ms., 1949-1961 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - The Drawing Room: An Inquiry Into the American Contribution to the Comedy of Manners, Columbia University, June 1956, (1 v. Carbon typescript of masters thesis, ) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - William Goldman's Columbia University Thesis: The Comedy of Manners in America, 1956, (2 t.ms, with autograph notes and marginalia), ) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 4.14: Diaries
    - Diary Goldman kept during the writing of The Thing of It Is (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 4.15: Research
    - Various
      - Autograph notes; Booklet of Military Publications Standard Abbreviated Job Titles; Beat in the Bronx; t.ms.; The Sudsy World of William Inge; t.ms.; fragment Beat in the Bronx;; untitled; t.ms; Anyone for Acupulco; t.ms.; untitled fragment (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Private notes and materials pertaining to Atlantic City; Pop culture photocopies of the early 1970s and untitled ms. (Box 9, Folder 3 & 4)
    - THE SEASON
      - John Bowen After the Rain original novel by J. Bowen (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Lawrence Holofcener Before You Go (Box 18, Folder Foloder 2)
      - Michael Voysey By George (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Robert Alan Arthur Carry Me Back to Morningside Heights (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - Stephen Levi Daphne in Cottage D (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - Peter Nichols A Day in the Life of Joe Egg (Box 18, Folder 6)
      - Benjamin Bernard Zavin The Education of Hyman Kaplan With words and music by Paul Nassau and Oscar Brand; based on stories created by Leo Rosten (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - Edward Albee Everything in the Garden (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - Lewis John Carlino The Exercise (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - Harvey Breit and Patricia Rinehart The Guide (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - Johnny No-Trump by Mary Mercier (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - Mike and Maggie Maggie and Mike by David Shaber (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - More Stately Mansions by Eugene O'Neil (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - I've Been Thinking by Herman Shumlin (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - Song of the Grasshopper by Alfonso Paso (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - Spring and Port Wine by Bill Naughton (Box 20, Folder 7)
      - The Unknown Soldier and his Wife by Peter Ustinov (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Weekend by Gore Vidal (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - What Did We Do Wrong by Henry Denker (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Clipping files for the 1967 - 1968 theater season (Box 21, Folder 4 - 6)
      - Clipping files for the 1967-1968 theater season includes loose draft pages (Box 22, Folder 1 - 6)
      - Clipping files for the 1967-1968 theater season; Research files, includes drafting material by W.G. regarding the state of the Tony Awards (Box 23, Folder 1 - 6)
      - Clipping files of the 1967-1968 theater season; Research files (Box 24, Folder 1 - 5)
      - Clipping files of the 1967-1968 theater season; Research files (Box 25, Folder 1 - 6)
      - Clipping files of the 1967-1968 theater season; Research files (Box 26, Folder 1 - 7)
      - Statistical notes; memorandum and theatrical indices regarding the 1967 - 68 theater; Research files (Box 27, Folder 1 - 7)
      - Theatrical surveys and indices of the 1967 - 68 theater season (Box 28, Folder 1 - 7)
      - Clipping files of the 1967-1968 theater season with William Goldman's manuscript notes (Box 29, Folder 1 - 7)
      - Draft of The Piano Man Ross MacDonald The Hot Rock research materials (Box 36, Folder 1 - 6)
      - Advance proof of The Goodbye Look by Ross MacDonald (Box 36, Folder 2)
      - W.G's notes on The Goodbye Look and a hardbound copy of The Hot Rock by Donald Westlake (Box 36, Folder 3)
      - Notes on Ross MacDonlad article and interview (Box 36, Folder 4)
      - Research materials for The Hot Rock (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - THE HOT ROCK
      - Drafts of scripts and research materials (Box 39, Folder 1 - 7)
    - THE GREAT WALDO PEPPER
      - Research materials (Box 39, Folder 4 - 7)
      - Research materials for The Great Waldo Pepper (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - THE STEPFORD WIVES
      - Born Female by Caroline Bird; The First Sex by Elizabeth Gould Davis (Box 57, Folder 1)
      - Women, Feminist Stories by Nine New Authords (Box 57, Folder 2)
      - Annotated draft of The Stepford Wives by Ira Levin (Box 57, Folder 3)
      - Research magazines (Box 57, Folder 4 - 7)
      - Magazines and clippings pertaining to the women's movement in the early 1970s (Box 58, Folder 1 - 5)
      - Drafts and other materials (Box 59, Folder 1 - 6)
      - Stepford Wives: Drafts of the screenplay and MPAA voting materials for the Academy Awards 1973 Academy Awards1973 voting material and wine related research for the screenplay Year of the Comet (Box 60, Folder 1 - 5)
    - YEAR OF THE COMET
      - Year of the Comet materials (Box 61, Folder 3 - 7)
      - Research materials and notes for The Year of the Comet (Box 62, Folder 1 - 4)
      - Research materials and copies of the third draft of The Year of the Comet (Box 64, Folder 1-6)
    - MARATHON MAN
      - Research materials for Marathon Man (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - WIGGER
      - Wigger notes (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - TOM HORN
      - The Last of the Bad Men by Jay Monaghan (Box 72, Folder 1)
      - Mr. Horn research and notes (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - ALL THE PRESIDENT'S MEN
      - Carbon copies of the novel All the President's Men (Box 75, Folder 4 - 6)
      - All The President's Men (1974); Carbon copies of book by Carl Bernstein and Bob Woodward (Box 76, Folder 1 - 5)
      - All The President's Men (1974); Research materials for the screenplay (Box 77, Folder 1 - 6)
      - All The President's Men (1974-1975); Research material / magazines (Box 78, Folder 1 - 7)
      - All the President's Men research material (Box 80, Folder 5 & 6)
      - All The President's Men, 1975 research and research notes (Box 81, Folder 1 & 2)
    - A BRIDGE TOO FAR
      - Reader's digest and A Full Life by Lt. Ge. Sir Brian Horrocks (Box 85, Folder 1 & 2)
      - Research, notes, and outlines for A Bridge too Far screenplay by W. Goldman (Box 85, Folder 3 - 7)
      - A Bridge too Far notes, script pages and research materials (Box 86, Folder 1 - 3)
      - Notes, memos research, script pages for A Bridge too Far (Box 86, Folder 5 & 6)
    - MAGIC
      - Magic research; personal files of W.G. at the time of Magic (Box 90, Folder 1 & 2)
      - Magic outline and notes (Box 90, Folder 7)
      - Personal notes (Box 92, Folder 5)
    - HEAT
      - Heat (1976-1984); Research files for W.G's novel (Box 93, Folder 1 - 6)
      - Research material (Box 94, Folder 1 - 3)
      - Production notes (Box 98, Folder 2)
    - BUTCH CASSIDY PROJECT
      - Research notes, outline and bio: Butch Cassidy, My Brother by Lula Parker Betenson as told to Dora Flack (Box 99, Folder 1)
      - Notes, script pages and research (Box 99, Folder 2 & 3)
    - GRAND HOTEL
      - Grand Hotel research materials (Box 101, Folder 4 - 6)
      - Five Decades short stories by Irwin Shaw (Box 102, Folder 2)
    - THE SEA KINGS
      - Research for The Sea Kings,; The Pirates by Douglas Botting (Box 102, Folder 4)
      - Notes for The Sea Kings (Box 103, Folder 1)
    - TINSEL
      - Research notes for i (Box 106, Folder 5 & six)
      - Notes for i (Box 107, Folder 1)
    - CONTROL
      - Research notes for Control (Box 110, Folder 3 - 6)
    - FLORA QUICK, DEAD OR ALIVE
      - Flora Quick, Dead or Alive screenplay by Michele Gallery, 1979; First and second drafts of the script Flora Quick, Dead or Alive by Michele Gallery (Box 114, Folder 1 - 6)
      - Flora Quick, Dead or Alive screenplay and City in Fear by Albert Ruben, 1979; Drafts of the screenplays (Box 115, Folder 1 - 5)
    - CITY IN FEAR
      - Draft Panic on Page One by Albert Ruben, aka City in Fear (Box 116, Folder 1)
      - City in Fear draft (Box 116, Folder 2)
    - MUCKALUCK
      - Muckaluck novel by Richard Anderson (Box 116, Folder 3)
      - Promotional notes and materials for Muckaluck (Box 116, Folder 4)
      - Draft of Muckaluck (Box 116, Folder 5)
    - A YEAR AND A DAY
      - Unidentified audio tape; A Year and a Day screenplay by Michael Leeson aka "Survivors" (Box 117, Folder 1)
      - First and second drafts of A Year and a Day by Michael Leeson (Box 117, Folder 2 - 8)
    - HOT SHOT
      - Hot Shot Research and notes (Box 118, Folder 1 - 4)
    - THE RIGHT STUFF
      - The Right Stuff research notes; This New Ocean, A History of Project Mercury by Lloyd S. Swnson, Jr. James Grimwood and Charles Alexander; The Right Stuff by Tom Wolfe (Box 120, Folder 2)
      - Notes and script pages for The Right Stuff (Box 121, Folder 1 - 3)
      - Notes (Box 122, Folder 1)
      - Notes on Rescue screenplay (Box 122, Folder 2)
      - Rescue screenplay, 1980-1981; Research, clippings and interviews for the novel Rescue (Box 124, Folder 1-6)
      - Reasearch, notes, and clippings for Rescue (Box 125, Folder 1 - 3)
      - Copies of first draft Rescue (Box 125, Folder 4 - 6)
      - First draft of Rescue (Box 126, Folder 1 & 2)
      - Rescue notes, clippings, research (Box 126, Folder 4 & 5)
      - Second and third draft of Rescue (Box 126, Folder 6 & 7)
      - Rescue third draft (Box 127, Folder 1)
      - Interview with John Brady (Box 127, Folder 3)
    - COLOR OF NIGHT
      - Notes and research for Color of Night (Box 127, Folder 5 - 8)
      - Research and notes for The Color of Night (Box 128, Folder 1 - 3)
    - ADVENTURES IN THE SCREEN TRADE
      - Research for Adventures in the Screen Trade (Box 131, Folder 1 - 5)
      - Adventures in the Screen Trade notes, research, draft pages (Box 132, Folder 1 - 6)
      - Research materials (Box 134, Folder 2)
    - BROTHERS
      - Brothers research material (Box 136, Folder 5 & 6)
      - Brothers (1987) notes and research (Box 137, Folder 1 - 6)
    - JOHN LENNON
      - John Lennon file (Box 141, Folder 2)
    - A CHORUS LINE
      - A Chorus Line playscript (Box 141, Folder 3)
      - A Chorus Line screenplay by Arnold Schulman (Box 141, Folder 4)
      - A Chorus Line, (1 audio cassette, ) (Box 141, Folder 5)
    - GHOST AND THE DARKNESS
      - The Lunatic Express by Charles Miller The Man Eaters of Tsavo by J.H. Patterson (Box 141, Folder 6)
      - The Man Eaters of Tsavo by J.H. Patterson (Box 142, Folder 1)
      - Research for the screenplay (Box 142, Folder 2 - 6)
      - The Iron Snake by Robert Hardy (Box 143, Folder 3 & 4)
    - WAIT UNTIL NEXT YEAR
      - Oberlin Commencement Address and Wait until Next Year unpublished nonfiction; research, 1985 (Box 152, Folder 1 - 7)
      - Wait Till Next Year research including notes, magazines, clippings, 1987 (Box 153, Folder 1- 5)
      - Wait Till Next Year research including notes, clippings, draft pages, magazines copy newspapers, 1987-1988 (Box 154, Folder 1 - 6)
      - Research (Box 155, Folder 1)
      - Research and draft pages (Box 155, Folder 2)
    - MEMOIRS OF AN INVISIBLE MAN
      - Memoirs of an Invisible Man by H.F. Saint (Box 157, Folder 2)
      - Notes, research and draft pages for Memoirs of an Invisible Man (Box 157, Folder 3 & 4)
    - KING BILL
      - King Bill (Box 160, Folder 2 & 3)
    - SIR RICHARD BURTON/SINGING OUT LOUD
      - Sir Richard Burton, a Biography, !987 (Box 161, Folder 1)
      - Sir Richard Burton notes (Box 161, Folder 2)
      - Singing Out Loud notes and research (Box 161, Folder 4)
      - Copy of screenplay Little Shop of Horrors (Box 161, Folder 5)
      - Grease by Bronte Woodward (Box 161, Folder 6)
      - West Side Story by Ernest Lehman (Box 162, Folder 1)
      - Singing in the Rain (Box 162, Folder 2)
      - Jesus Christ Superstar (Box 162, Folder 3)
    - HYPE AND GLORY
      - 1988 Cannes Film Festival ephemera (Box 166, Folder 1 - 6)
      - Research pertaining to the Miss America Contest, 1987 (Box 167, Folder 1 - 6)
      - The Miss America Contest materials (Box 168, Folder 1 - 7)
    - MISERY
      - Notes on Misery (Box 174, Folder 2)
    - A FEW GOOD MEN
      - Original play by Aaron Sorkin (Box 179, Folder 1)
    - UNHOLY CITY
      - Sunshine and Wealth, Los Angeles in the Twenties and Thirties by Bruce Henstell and other research (Box 180, Folder 2)
      - Munson case information (Box 180, Folder 3)
      - Papers regarding the Civic Committee in the Recall of Mayor Frank Shaw (Box 180, Folder 4)
      - Urban Politics and Reform in New Deal Los Angeles: The Recall of Mayor Frank L. Shaw (Box 180, Folder 5)
      - Urban Politics and Reform in New Deal Los Angeles: The Recall of Mayor Frank L. Shaw (Box 181, Folder 1)
      - The Progressives and the Police: Urban Reform and Professionalism of the Los Angeles Police (Box 181, Folder 2 - 4)
      - Copies of magazine articles (Box 181, Folder 5)
      - Various research materials, 1989-1990 (Box 182, Folder 1 - 6)
    - THE NATIONAL PASTIME
      - Research notes for The National Pastime (Box 185, Folder 3- 5)
    - LOW FIVES
      - Low Fives research and first drafts (Box 191, Folder 2 - 6)
    - CHAPLIN
      - Chaplin based on My Autobiography by Charles Chaplin and His Life and Art by David Robinson, Story by Diana Hawkins, screenplay by William Boyd and William Goldman (Box 193, Folder 3 - 6)
      - Hunchback of Notre Dame by Victor Hugo and other research (Box 196, Folder 5 & 6)
    - MAVERICK
      - Poker Faces, The Life and Work of professional Card Players by David M. Hayano (Box 197, Folder 7)
      - Notes, research and drafts of the screenplay, 1992-1993 (Box 197, Folder 1 - 6)
    - THE CHAMBER
      - Draft and research (Box 201, Folder 3 - 6)
      - Absolute Power Chapter breakdown (Box 205, Folder 1)
      - The Executive Power by David Baldacci (four marked copy of the novel) (Box 205, Folder 2 - 4)
      - Absolute Power screenplay, Cannes '96 Ephemera and Mission Impossible 2 research, 1996 (Box 209, Folder 1-2)
      - Screenplay 1999, research materials (Box 210, Folder 1 - 6)
      - "Terrorist Project" research materials (Box 211, Folder 3 - 8)
    - BROTHERS
      - New York Times Magazine 4 March 1984, 4 March 1984 (Box 528, Folder 9)
    - STEPFORD WIVES
      - Oversize feminist newspaper (Box 529, Folder 6)
    - BUTCH AND SUNDANCE
      - Oversize nrewspapers (Box 529, Folder 7 & 8)
      - Oversize nrewspapers (Box 529, Folder 7 & 8)
    - GRAND HOTEL